上帝保佑 菩萨保佑 佛祖保佑
Please, please, please, please.
你们在干嘛啊
Okay, what is this?
在确认我身高已经足够
We're making sure I'm tall enough
可以乘坐迪斯尼乐园所有设施
to ride all the rides at Disneyland.
不用把头发竖成钉耙冒充高个儿
Without having to spike up my hair.
老弟
Buddy...
完全合格
We are good to go.
帅呆了
Sweet!
我期待这一天已经很久了
I have been waiting for this day
自从医生指着你妈的
ever since the doctor pointed
子宫超声波图对我说
to the ultrasound of your mom's womb and said,
"那货如果不是有五肢
"Either that's a fifth limb,
那么你就要抱儿子了"
or you got a boy."
别说了 真恶心
Okay, no. Gross.
听好 大家今天都在家把饭吃饱了
All right... I want everybody to eat a lot at home
因为世上最销魂的极乐之地
because "The happiest place on earth"
卖的西班牙油条也贵得离谱
is also home to the most expensive churro on earth.
拜托 一定会爽翻天的
Come on. This is gonna be awesome.
谁不爱迪斯尼一日游呢
Who doesn't love a day at Disneyland?
你们就不能放过我吗
Can't you and mom go without me?
你是小孩 小孩就应该去
You're the kid. I think we need you to get in.
非得挑今天这么个日子
Well, it couldn't come on a worst day.
科技板块正在大跳水呢
The technology sector is tanking.
学校布置了一个股票市场模拟的作业
We're doing a stock market project in school,
今天是最后一天了
and today's the last day.
我们每人有一千元代币用来投资
We all get a thousand fake dollars to invest,
到昨天闭市为止
and as the market closed yesterday,
我独占鳌头
I'm in the lead.
小哥我身高不突出 运动不拔尖
I may not be the tallest or the most athletic,
但有朝一日我绝对是大款
but someday I will be the richest,
妹子们都爱傍大款
which is good because the ladies love that,
鉴于我爹妈的配对情况 我已经习惯了
and I've grown accustomed to a certain lifestyle.
你真会喜欢那些看重你钱的姑娘吗
Do you really wants girls who only want you for your money?
我希望自己有那个选择权
I'd like to have that option.
曼尼 别管股市了 把米老鼠耳朵戴上
Manny, put the stock away and put your ears on.
妈 我不用戴这个吧
Mom, I don't think you have to wear one of these.
像个小孩样 给娘戴上
Be a kid! Put them on!
没搞错吧 穿这双鞋
Really? Those shoes?
怎么了
What?
你知道在迪斯尼乐园得走多少路吗
Do you know how much walking you have to do at Disneyland?
没瞅见那群懒胖子都用滑板车来代步吗
Why do you think they have so many fat people on scooters?
我就喜欢高跟鞋 我没事
I like wearing the high heels. I'm fine.
就跟上次我让你带件外套
It's just like that jacket you refuse to bring
而你宁死不听的情况一样
when I say, "Take a jacket."
"别老对我紫手画脚 我没事"
"Don't tell me what to do! I'm fine!"
结果呢 你才不是没事
Huh? And you're not fine.
你又冷又冻
You're cold and shivering,
我则像个连外套都不肯脱给老婆的混球一样
and I look like the jerk who won't give his wife a jacket,
于是只好把外套给你 结果自己受冷受冻
so I do, and then I'm cold and shivering,
可明明我自己就带了外套的
and I brought a jacket.
你那叨逼叨的外套故事完了没
Are you done with your boring jacket story?
再继续说就要赶上大塞车了
Because we're going to hit traffic.
我就一句话 到时候可别想穿我的鞋
Tell you one thing. I'm not gonna give you my shoes.
哈 一定是伊森到了
Ah! That must be Ethan.
伊森是谁啊
Who's Ethan?
我没告诉你们吗
Didn't I tell you?
我朋友贝瑟妮的侄子今天和我们一起去
My friend Bethenny's nephew is coming with us today.
他为了上大学方便搬家至此
He moved to town to go to college.
他人超和善 超聪明 还会玩冰球
He's very nice, very smart, big hockey player.
我看穿你在耍什么花样了
I know what you're doing.
真的吗 她说得这么"隐晦"
Really? She was so subtle.
海莉总是喜欢坏男生
Haley has a thing for bad boys,
真是有其母必有其女
which was so me.
显然嘛
Clearly.
如果她即将离巢而去
So if she's going to be leaving the nest soon,
也最好不要是骑在摩托后座走的
we'd prefer it was not on the back of a motorcycle.
我大学室友就有辆摩托
My college roommate had a motorcycle.
我当年在车后座度过了很多幸福的时光
Man, I had some good times on the back of that thing.
真不敢相信你会这么做
I can't believe you did this.
我可不要照顾贝瑟妮的侄儿 交给艾丽克斯了
I'm not gonna babysit Bethenny's nephew. Alex can have him.
被你拒绝的次品我可不稀罕
Okay, I don't need your rejects.
伊森 真高兴你能来
Hi, Ethan! I'm so glad you could make it.
谢谢您邀请我
Thanks for inviting me.
没事
Sure.
你好 我叫艾
Hi. I'm Al--
她是我14岁的小妹 伊森 对吧
my 14-year-old sister. Ethan, was it?
没错
Yeah.
那是我外公和他老婆歌洛莉亚
And that's my grandpa and his wife Gloria
还有她儿子曼尼
and her son Manny.
你们真是个大家庭啊
Wow. You guys have a big family.
大家庭呢
Big family.
她挺中意他的
She likes him!
谁能不中意啊
Yeah, who wouldn't?
哪找来的 汤米·席尔菲格成衣目录吗
Where'd you find him, a Tommy Hilfiger catalog?
他高考考了2200分
He got a 2200 on his S.A.T.S.
那双摄魂美眸
And those eyes...
你是在挑女婿还是在找老公啊
Okay, did you get him for Haley or for you?
米奇尔
Mitchell.
自从小时候跟爸一起来之后 我就再也没来过了
You know, I haven't been here since dad brought us when we were kids.
对 记得吗 你还为那亚伯拉罕·林肯哭了
Ohh, yeah. Remember? You cried in the Abraham Lincoln thing.
人家是伟大的总统
Hey, he's a great president,
况且我也是头一回看见机器人
and it was the first robot I ever saw.
克莱尔和米奇尔小时候
When Claire and Mitchell were young,
我和他们妈妈准备带他们去迪斯尼乐园玩
their mom and I were gonna take them to Disneyland.
那天早上 迪迪和我大吵一架
But that morning, Dede and I got in this huge fight
就为了些鸡毛蒜皮的小事
over something or other-- surprise, surprise--
最后我只好独自带他们去
and I ended up taking them on my own.
克莱尔的噩梦是撞见那邪恶皇后
Claire's biggest fear was running into the evil queen.
我的噩梦是已经娶回家一个邪恶皇后
My biggest fear was that I married her.
身高超过1米17的同志们
Okay, people over 46 inches,
第一站 印第安纳琼斯
first stop--Indiana Jones!
莉莉 你就在茶杯转盘里好好玩吧
Have fun on the teacups, Lily.
大家出发吧
Okay, let's do this.
各位 先等一下
Oh, okay, wait just a second here, everybody.
好了
All right.
你那是根遛狗绳吗
Is that a leash?
不 是孩童安全系绳 走这边 乖女儿
No, it's a child safety tether. This way, sweetie.
那就是根遛狗绳
It--it's a leash.
别对我们评判指责
Don't--don't judge us.
来吧
Go on.
我们家有个乱窜鬼
We have a runner.
莉莉正处于某种阶段
Lily is going through a phase--
至少 我们希望这只是阶段现象
at least... Oh, we hope it's a phase.
她一逮到机会就往外窜
She bolts every chance she gets.
莉莉
Lily!
我们别无选择
So we had no choice
只能给她系上儿童安全系绳
to put her on a child safety tether.
就是根遛狗绳
It's a leash.
我们当然可以选择不系
And we did have a choice.
莉莉 宝贝 别拉绳子
Lily, sweetie, don't pull.
莉莉 跟紧
Lily, heel!
爸爸
Dad.
早知道你们会玩这个把戏
If I'd had known you guys were gonna do this,
我就把斯黛拉也牵来了
I'd have brought Stella.
都是小卡的主意
It was Cam's idea.
"多谢"你和我站在同一战线上
So much for the united front.
告诉你 你尽管笑吧 莉莉自己享受就好
I'll have you know, despite all your jokes, Lily enjoys it.
宝贝 别学狗叫 你就别添乱了
Okay, sweetie, you're not helping. You're not helping.
我的天 你们快看 那不是迪兰吗
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. You guys, is that Dylan?
什么
What?
老天
Oh, jeez.
迪兰
Dylan?!
你在干嘛 我都不知道你回城了
Uh, what are you... I didn't even know you were in town.
我也不知道
Either did I...
不知道你在城里
Know you were in town.
我是说迪斯尼小城 阿纳海姆
This town. Anaheim.
我以为你还在怀俄明州呢
I thought you were still in Wyoming.
我的确是
I was, uh...
不过
But, um...
糟了
Oh, shoot.
我还得和几个朋友碰面
You know, I, uh, gotta meet up with some friends
我已经迟到了
and I'm... really late.
很高兴见到你 海莉
It was nice to see you, Haley,
还有大家
and everybody.
还有我不认识的这位
And dude I don't know.
我叫伊森 很高兴见到你
I'm Ethan. It's nice to meet you.
彬彬有礼 可惜我还是不认识
And polite dude I don't know.
海莉以前和那人交往过吗
Did Haley used to date that guy or something?
没错 你要是和她交往 就和他是同等级的货色了
Yep. You date her, that's the club you're joining. Mm.
他真是风采不减当年
Of course he would still look amazing.
有吗 我怎么没觉得
Does he? I hadn't noticed.
伊森会吹小号你知道吗
Did you know that Ethan plays the trumpet?
难怪有那么性感的嘴唇 是吧
No great surprise with those lips of his, huh?
一切进展顺利啊 鲁宾逊太太
Coo-coo-ca-choo, Mrs. Robinson.
好了伙计 测量真相的时刻了
Okay, buddy, moment of truth.
好哎
Yes!
可要玩到爽翻天啊
This is gonna be so awesome! Yeah!
再等45分钟 玩到爽翻天啊
In 45 minutes, this is gonna be so awesome!
听着罗本
Look, Reuben,
我手头有不少垃圾股要抛
I have some underperformers I have to unload,
可现在周围没电脑可以连上网
and I don't have access to a computer.
用"钱爷·迪尔加多"的名字登录
Log in as moneydelgado--
曼尼
Manny!
快想办法去 罗本
By all means, Reuben,
"日经指数"闭市了再去吃冰棒好吗
go get a popsicle while the nikkei closes.
别让我变成穷鬼
I wanna be a pauper.
妈 我那支股票突然暴跌
Mom, my stocks just took a dive.
你再说我把你手机跌水里去
Your phone is about to take a dive.
赶紧的 我们下一站去哪
Come on! Where do we want to go next?
伊森和我想去"幽灵公馆"里探险
Oh! Ethan and I want to try the haunted mansion.
你可别趁机勾搭伊森
There is no you and Ethan.
我们去丛林探险吧 就在那不远
Let's go to the jungle cruise. It's right there.
咋了 厌倦了穿高跟鞋走远路吗
Why? Tired of walking in those heels?
没 你会厌倦性感火辣的娇妻吗
No. You tired of being with a hot wife?
哎呦 你瞅瞅 可真没料到
Well, well, well. What do you know?
又一个负责任的家长在用儿童安全系绳
Another caring parent with a child safety tether.
看 我们又不是唯一在用的
See? We're not the only people who use them.
你家小孩真可爱
Hi! Aren't they adorable?
瞧瞧你家小可爱
Oh, and look at your cutie!
可不是嘛 她就想打个招呼
Oh, well, yes. She just wanted to say hi.
不好意思 他俩今天有点小毛躁
Oh. Sorry. They're a little feisty today.
没关系 她脾气挺好
Oh! No problem. She's friendly.
雷克斯 礼貌点
Rex, gentle.
他叫雷克斯[霸王龙] 对吧
Oh, his--his name's Rex, huh?
是的
Yeah.
那什么 莉莉 宝贝 莉莉...
Oh, okay. Lily, no, sweetie. Lily, um...
抱歉 他就是有点人来疯
Oh. Sorry. He--he just gets excited.
是啊 没关系
Oh, yeah, no--oh, no problem.
莉莉 别跑了 亲爱的 停下来
Lily, stop moving, sweetie. Stop moving.
好的 交给你了
Okay, you got this.
好嘞 好嘞 乖女儿 乖女儿 抱歉
Okay. Okay. Good girl! Good girl! Sorry.
想知道那次我为啥要和迪迪吵吗
You know what the fight with Dede was about?
我录橄榄球比赛时洗掉了一集《达拉斯豪门恩怨》
I taped a football game over an episode of "Dallas."
谁会就此撇下全家 拒绝一起去迪斯尼
Who bails on a family trip to Disneyland
就为那么点鸡毛蒜皮的小事
over something like that?
讽刺的是 达拉斯那场比赛还上场了
Ironically, Dallas was playing in the game.
我当时还指给她看来着
And I remember pointing that out to her,
再接着我就记得
and then I remember
一盒录影带朝我脑门飞了过来
a video cassette flying at my head.
你不是真的拉大提琴吧
You do not play the cello.
是的 虽说有点怪咖 我不在乎
I do. Even geekier--I'm good.
那好 回答我一个问题
Okay, answer me this--
回答你十个问题都行
I will answer you this.
为什么人们总是随身拖着大提琴
Why do people carry cellos around?
也没见人拖着钢琴到处走啊
You know, people aren't expected to lug a piano around.
原因不同在哪里
What's the cutoff?
可不是嘛 大提琴 任我行
I know, right? Like, go where the cello is.
瞧瞧他们 我无心插了一柳
Oh, look at this. I think I've inadvertently
倒是给一14岁小萝莉和一大学男孩遮上了荫
set up my 14-year-old with a college boy.
那男孩是你找来的
The boy was your doing?
是啊 是啊 完美的男子
Yes. Yes, and he was perfect,
海莉之前对他还是挺有好感的
and Haley was into him until,
直到我们撞见了迪兰
of course, we ran into Dylan.
说真的 怎么会有那么巧的事情
I mean, come on, dad. What are the odds of that happening?
这世界小得很
It's a small world.
可不是嘛
Yes, it is.
-瞧见我刚刚的风采了吗 -我懂
- You see what I did there? - I did.
-一把年纪疯狂玩 -我懂 我懂 老爸
- 'Cause it's a ride. - I got it. Got it, dad. I got it.
真是让我太沮丧了...
It's so frustrating because...
我知道我不能替海莉做主
I know I can't run Haley's life for her,
不过如果她同意了 我肯定干得特别棒
but if she would let me, I would be so good at it.
对啊 父母可是最会替孩子着想了
Right, 'cause parents always know what's best for their kids.
还记得我办公室里那个好女孩
You remember that nice girl at the office
就是我打算介绍个米奇的那个吗
I tried to fix Mitch up with?
无意冒犯 不过在理解孩子的"需求"方面
No offense, dad, but I think I probably have
我的能力应该是比你更胜一筹的
a better sense of what my kids need than you did.
你这么想可真是天真
I think it's cute you think that.
老妈
Mom!
玩得真是爽极了
It was so awesome!
那车到处乱窜
The jeep was jerking around...
那里到处是急转弯和大坡度
And--and there was a lot of sharp turns and big drops.
它还继续往前开
It just kept going.
你还好吗
Wow. You okay?
好得很 怎么会不好
Great. Why wouldn't I be?
因为我感觉你需要我的搀扶
Because you're kinda leaning on me.
婚姻不就是要相互扶持吗
Well, isn't that what a marriage is?
艾丽克斯 放开那个男孩
Ohh. Oh, Alex, stop touching him.
你看上去糟透了
Oh. You look like hell.
我晕头转向 满眼金星
I'm feeling a little dizzy.
估计是刚才那一趟车给坐的
I think that ride did something to me.
你内耳中的液体会变浓
The fluid in your inner ear is thickening.
身体老化时就会这样
That's what happens when you get old.
是吗
It is?
某些动作你已经消受不起了
Yeah, you can't take the motion.
我坐旋转椅之前都得先来颗"晕海宁"
I gotta pop a dramamine to get in my swivel chair.
才不是那样 我可是过山车之王
That is not it. I'm king of the roller coasters.
我觉得是因为
I think I just put
早上我往烤饼里放太多生奶油了
too big of a whipped cream smile on my pancake this morning.
你俩想去马特洪峰上看看吗
You guys wanna go on matterhorn?
卢克 我和你爸还是坐这等你吧
Luke, I think me and your dad are gonna sit this one out,
或许弄一大份腌黄瓜分着吃
maybe get one them big pickles.
不 腌黄瓜你自己吃吧 杰
No! You're gonna have to eat that pickle on your own, Jay.
我尚有几年年轻力壮的日子呢
I still got a few good years left.
卢克 等等我
Luke, wait up!
比比谁先到那
I'll race you there!
我没事 我没事
I'm good. I'm good.
每个人都在盯着咱
Okay, everybody's looking at us.
我已经很久没被这么多人围观过了
I haven't been judged by this many people
上次还是去全食市场忘带帆布包
since I forgot my canvas bags at whole foods.
他们盯着我们可能是因为
Yeah, well, maybe they're staring
对我们美好生活的羡慕嫉妒恨
because we have what they want.
你是在说我们的"宠物闺女"吗
Whoa! Oh, a pet daughter. 'Cause that...
旁人说什么我可不在乎
You know, I don't care what people think.
只要我觉得可以保证我家闺女的安全
If I thought it would keep my daughter safe,
让我在腹部缝一个袋鼠育儿袋我都愿意
I would have a kangaroo pouch sewn into my midriff.
你身为单亲家长 这么一来是挺方便
That's gonna work out really well for you as a single parent.
那"短袜凉脱"男诧异地看了我们一眼
Okay, we just got a glare from Mr. Socks-with-sandals.
好了 我受够了
All right, that's it.
莉莉 我来替你把这遛狗绳给解了
Lily, I'm gonna take off this leash.
我觉得这样做是不对的
I think it's a mistake.
但同时我也不希望你会乱跑
But I don't want you to run away,
因为那样非常 非常危险
'cause that would be very, very unsafe,
一旦我们找不着你
and if we lost you,
你会惊恐万分 我们会悲痛欲绝 好吗
you'd be very scared, and we'd be very sad. Okay?
好的
Okay.
很好
All right.
看 小卡 你若把她当个人对待
See, Cam? You treat her like a human being
她就会以人的标准要求自己
and she acts like one.
《奇奇与蒂蒂》
Chip 'n Dale!
这下好了 她去追松鼠去了 莉莉
Oh, great. Now she's chasing squirrels. Lily!
亲爱的 别跑
Honey, come on!
莉莉 莉莉
Lily! Lily!
"激流勇进"好玩吗
Hey! How was Splash Mountain?
棒极了 要不我们再玩一次
It was great! Maybe we go again.
我就免了 里面连手机信号都没有
No, thanks. There was no reception in there.
知道刚刚我手机有几格信号吗 完全没有
You know how many bars I had? Zip-a-Dee-doo-dah.
罗本 赶紧汇报
Reuben, talk to me!
你要是脱了鞋休息一会儿肯定特舒坦
Must be nice to get out of those shoes for a minute.
你这是在说什么呢
I don't know what you talking about.
没啥 就随便唠唠
Nothing. I'm just making conversation.
快来看看
Hey. Check it out.
我这有张你们刚玩"激流勇进"时
I bought one of those souvenir photos
你和曼尼拍下的纪念照
with you and Manny on the ride.
老天 你刚才真是玩得挺爽
Boy, it looks like you're having a good time.
等下 你手里拿的是什么啊
Wait a minute. What's that in your hand?
是双高跟鞋吗
Are those shoes?
这么模糊我都看不清是谁 杰
I'm not even sure that that is us, Jay.
你为什么要忍着痛走路
Why are you walking around in pain?
你就承认吧 穿这鞋来就不合适
Just admit the shoes were a bad idea.
我可没感觉到痛
I am not in pain.
我就是怕我最爱的鞋给弄湿了而已
I just didn't want my favorite walking shoes to get wet there.
好吧 我错了
Okay, my bad.
我们还得去"明日世界"和大家会合呢
Well, we've gotta meet everybody in Tomorrowland,
所以赶紧走吧
so we'd better get movin'
那地方可是在公园的另一边呢
'cause it's all the way on the other side of the park.
我好得很
I'm fine.
你可别让我们给甩下了
You just try to keep up with us.
我看不下去了
I can't take this.
爸 把手松开 太刺激了
Dad, throw your hands up! It's fun!
是啊 真刺激
Oh, yeah, it is fun!
罗本 如果你是在生日聚会上听说那股票的
Reuben, if you heard about that stock at a birthday party,
那就已经晚了
it's already too late.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
歌洛莉亚 坐会儿
Gloria, sit down for a second.
杰 我没事
I'm fine, Jay.
求你了
Please?
听我说
Look...
你也许不痛苦
You may not be in pain...
好吧
Okay.
但只要觉得你痛苦 我就会痛苦
But I'm in pain just thinking you're in pain.
所以 你就乖乖听我一回
So humor me for one minute.
这是什么
What are those?
"灰姑娘"小店里没多少款式可供选择
There wasn't a big selection at the Bibbidi Bobbidi Boutique.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
我不能在大庭广众之下穿着...
I cannot walk around in public with these...
这种东西走路 又黄有丑
Things. They're so yellow and so ugly.
而且还很软
And... and they're so softy
很舒服
and so comfortable.
杰 这是什么
Jay, what is this?
谢谢你给我买了这个
Thank you for going shopping for me.
谢谢你心疼我的脚
Thank you for worrying about my feet.
谢谢你在我冷的时候把外套给我穿
Thank you for giving me your jacket when I'm cold.
杰 你真是个好男人
You're such a good man, Jay.
谢谢
Thank you. Mmm.
没想到你突然变得这么...
I didn't expect you to be so...
温柔
So nice.
你为何如此惊讶
Why are you so surprised?
我说这话 你可别生气
Now please don't go all Latin on me when I say this.
莫非
Is it possible
你总发无名火的原因是
you get angry from time to time
你脚下穿的一直是
because you're always wearing...
让你搓火的鞋子
Uncomfortable shoes?
可能吧
Maybe.
能再给我买几双这样的鞋吗
Can you get me a couple of more?
说不定有紫色的
Maybe they have purple?
你想要啥都行 宝贝
Whatever you want, honey.
我是说
All I'm saying is,
你似乎很喜欢伊森
it seemed like you were pretty into Ethan
直到迪兰出现
until Dylan showed up.
别误会我 伊森人很好 但他不是迪兰
Don't get me wrong. Ethan's nice, but he's no Dylan.
那不是好事吗
Maybe that's a good thing?
为什么 就因为迪兰自由随性吗
Why? Because Dylan's a free spirit?
是因为他太前卫了吗
He's too edgy for you?
还是因为他的特立独行
He plays by his own rules?
天呐
Oh, my God.
怎么了
What?
我想请你转身
I beg of you to turn around
和我一同见证我此生最难忘的一幕
and experience with me the greatest moment of my life.
你的叛逆男友变成了四重奏歌手
Your rebel boyfriend's a Dapper Dan.
也许我们看错了
Maybe that's not him.
迪兰
Dylan!
对不起
Uh, uh, sorry.
Sorry. Um...
确实很像他
It certainly seems like him.
天呐 他看起来
Oh, my God. He looked like
像老爸高中时的旧照片
those old pictures of dad from high school.
反正 我最近爱上街头艺术了
So anyway, I've really been into street art lately.
城里有个展览很不错 我带你去吧
Oh, there's a really great exhibit downtown. I'll take you.
怎么去 用你那"劲爆"踏板车去吗
Oh, on what, your razor scooter?
老妈找你
Mom wants you.
我 我 我
I-I-I...
伊森 我到处找你呢
Ethan! I've been looking all over for you!
我记得当时是在玩"加勒比海盗"
I remember I was on Pirates of the Caribbean,
跟迪迪吵得那一架真是太闹心了
and this whole fight with Dede was really eating at me.
游乐项目中有个疯婆娘
And there was this angry animatronic wench
拿着擀面杖 追着个可怜的海盗
with a rolling pin, chasing some poor pirate around.
他俩绕着一个圆环不停转圈
They were on a track, running in circles,
也就是说他永远摆脱不了她
so he could never get away from her.
我当时就在想
And I remember thinking,
哥们 我是救不了你
I can't save you, buddy,
但我要结束我自己的婚姻之旅
but I'm getting off this ride.
然后 然后我们正要拐弯
...and--and we were going around a corner,
我尖叫了 吃进了一只虫子
and I was screaming and I swallowed a bug.
我最喜欢坐最后一节车厢了
Oh, being tail is everything that I dreamed it would be.
接下来该干啥呢
What should we do next?
坐下
Sit down.
我们坐哪儿
Where we gonna sit down?
坐地上就这儿 坐这儿就好
The ground. Here, this is good right here. Oh!
爸 你没事吧
Are you okay, dad?
我不行了
No, I'm not okay.
虽然我不想承认
I hate to tell you this,
可这一趟趟车坐的我命都快没了
but these rides are killing me.
你可是过山车之王啊
B-but you're the king of roller coasters.
我知道
I know!
岁月不饶人啊
Something happens when you get older.
身体已经吃不消了
Guess you can't take it.
我这辈子最喜欢干的事儿
One of my favorite things in the world
就是和你一起做傻事
is doing stupid fun stuff with you,
比如踩着跳跳鼠打篮球
like pogo stick basketball
以及试图把秋千荡一整个圈
or trying to get a swing to go all the way around.
下一次咱试试坐在灭火器上
Next time, we should sit on a fire extinguisher.
好 或者是可乐加薄荷糖
Yes, or a bottle of coke and some mentos.
不过说实话 我现在的感受是
Honestly, though, the way I'm feeling right now,
不知道自己还能不能活到那时候
I don't know if there's gonna be a next time.
爸 我们总能找到好玩的事儿干
Dad, we can always find cool stuff to do.
哪怕你老了 坐在轮椅里
Even if you're old and in a wheelchair,
我会带你到商场
I'll take you to the mall
你想飞多快 我就推多快
and push you as fast as you wanna go.
真的吗
Really?
你会那么做吗
You'd do that?
必须的
Heck, yeah.
再试试玩轮椅特技
And we'll pop some wheelies, too.
听起来不错哦
That sounds fun.
我还会把你推到山顶上 然后放手
And I'll take you to the top of a huge hill and just let go.
好吧 细节我们以后好商量
Okay, we'll nail down the specifics later,
不过听起来真棒
but that... That's really nice.
你还想接着聊吗
So do you still wanna talk or--
不聊了 去玩"飞跃太空山"吧
No, go. Ride Space Mountain.
最后他们照相时
Uh, at the end, when they take a picture,
做搞怪的动作吧 算我一个
do something hilarious for both of us.
那会要了你的命的
You're gonna die.
我是说你看到会笑死的 不是说你太老了
When you see it, not 'cause you're old.
莉莉 莉莉 别跑
Lily! Lily, stop!
爸爸 爸爸 抓住她
Dad! Dad, grab her!
抓住你了 你这小猴子
Hey, I gotcha, you little monkey!
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿 小卡 我逮住她了
Hey, Cam, I got her.
我们在"幻想世界" 你们在哪儿
We're in Fantasyland. Where are you?
好吧 那是叫"卡通城"
Okay, it's toontown,
不是"卡咚城"
not toonton.
你看太多PBS电视台的剧了
You've been watching too much PBS.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧 宝贝 过来
All right, honey, come here.
我不喜欢这东西
I don't like this thing.
是嘛
Yeah?
我还不想像个疯子一样
Well, I don't like running like a crazy person
在《唐顿迪斯尼庄园》跑来跑去呢
through Downton Disney--
"迪斯尼市镇"
Downtown Disney.
我不知道做什么好
I don't know what to do.
遛狗绳既然行不通 让我给你指条明路
Well, the leash is not the answer. You want my help?
快帮帮我吧
Yes, please!
给我两分钟 我就能帮你搞定
'Cause I can fix this for you in about two minutes.
来吧 小姑娘 跟我走
Come on, baby girl. Come with me.
我们马上就回来
We'll be right back.
好的
Okay.
我们要去哪儿 这边吗
Where we going? Oh, this way?
曼尼 你这张苦逼脸不像是来
Manny, you don't sound very happy
开开心心坐"小飞象"的孩子啊
for a kid that is flying an elephant.
我输给德卡斯了 这不公平
I lost to Durkas. It's not fair.
他想买下IBM 因为他觉得这听起来很有趣
He wanted to buy IBM because he thought it was funny to say.
好吧 我很高兴你输了
Well, I'm glad that you lost.
模拟经营游戏让你变了
Fake money has changed you.
从前那个会停下来赏花的曼尼去哪儿了
Where is the Manny that used to stop to smell the roses?
他搬到圣何塞 洗上太阳能热水澡了呢
He took a bath on a solar start-up in San Jose.
你一整天都电话不离手
You have been so busy burying your face in your phone
跟家人连个招呼都不打
that you barely said hello to your family,
对维尼熊也是爱理不理
you gave Winnie the Pooh the cold shoulder,
甚至都没注意到
and you haven't even noticed
那边蓝色小象里的小美女
that pretty girl in the blue elephant
一直冲着你笑呢
that has been smiling at you.
虽说不是我的型 但被人欣赏终究不错
Not my type, but still it's nice to be noticed.
瞧见没
You see what happens
你醉心生意错过了多少幸福时光
when you're not burying your head in business?
你说的对 我尽量享受当下吧
You're right. I'll try to be more present.
你脚上是什么东西
What the heck's on your feet?
拖鞋 软得和枕头一样
They're slippers! They're like pillows.
小乖乖
Attagirl.
不用谢我
You're welcome.
看 你爸给他孙女买了高跟鞋
Look. Your dad got her baby high heels,
咱不是说过绝不让她穿吗
which we said we were never gonna let her wear.
我喜欢这鞋
I love 'em.
你看起来真漂亮 宝贝
You look gorgeous, sweetie.
老天 想想刚才旁人对咱的嫌弃劲儿
Oh, my gosh. You felt people judged us before?
现在却是阿纳海姆选美小冠军
Wait till they meet little Miss Anaheim.
那倒还好 不过她是走都走不利索了
Who cares? Look at her. She can barely move.
多谢了 老爸
Thank you, dad.
知道吗 三岁的女娃就有这美腿 真难得
You know what? She's got pretty good gams for a 3-year-old.
茄子
Cheese!
好了 谢谢 约翰熊
Got it. Thanks, little John.
谢谢
Thank you!
那边有卖玉米热狗的
Ooh, they have corn dogs.
回家前一定得吃一个 绝世美味
We gotta get one before we go back. They are legendary.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
好的
Okay.
海莉
Haley!
是我 迪兰
It's me. Dylan.
我穿着熊戏服 专门借来好跟你说话
I'm in the bear suit. I borrowed it to talk to you.
你为什么要这样跳舞
Why are you dancing like that?
约翰熊就是这样跳的 可能吧
This is what little John does. Maybe.
我不知道这货出自哪部电影
I don't know what movie this dude is from.
我根本不应该跟你讲话的
I'm not even supposed to be talking to you.
我也不想跟你说
Well, I'm not talking to you.
不 你可以说话
No, you can talk.
我知道 可我气得说不出
I know, but I'm mad.
你回到家都不给我打个电话
You came back to town and didn't even call me.
我觉得太丢人了
I was embarrassed.
我丢掉了度假牧场的工作
I lost my job at the dude ranch,
我得先理清头绪
and I wanted to get my act together first.
四傻蛋骑单车有用吗
But the four dweebs on a bike act?
四重唱可是街头表演的老传统
Hey, the dapper dans are a main street tradition
1959年就开始了
since 1959.
这是怎么回事
Hey, what's going on?
没什么
Nothing.
我还爱着她 伊森
I still love her, Ethan.
你怎么知道我的名字
Okay, how do you know my name?
我是迪兰
It's Dylan.
我今天不是故意来给你添堵
Look, I don't wanna harsh your day,
但我一直爱着海莉 而且会爱到地老天荒
but I never stopped loving Haley and I never will!
你这是在演滑稽戏呢
I-is this some sort of joke?
我看起来很滑稽吗
Do I look like I'm joking?
迪兰 现在别这样
Dylan, let's not do this now.
就得现在 我三点还得参加游行
It has to be now. I've got a parade at 3:00.
说真的哥们 边儿呆着去
Hey, seriously, dude, back off.
首先 这可是我的脸
Okay, that was my face.
再者 该一边凉快的人是你
And you're the one who needs to back off.
你...
You...
好吧 这套衣服还挺重的
Okay. This thing's kinda heavy.
我起不来了
I can't get up.
伊森 伊森 怎么啦 你在做什么
Ethan? Ethan, what is going on? What are you doing?
你好 邓菲太太
Uh, hi, Mrs. Dunphy.
搭把手
Help me up.
不
No.
可别让我起来 要不我一定...
If I could get up, I would--uhh!
快点 莉莉宝贝 跟上 亲爱的
Come on, Lily sweetie. Keep up, honey.
-快点 -菲尔 你看起来没什么精神啊
- Come on. - Phil, you don't look like you're doing very well.
可能是因为刚才在雷鸣山我正式
Maybe because I officially became an old man
体会到了这身老骨头的脆弱
back there at thunder mountain.
我的天 你好烫啊
Oh, my goodness. You are burning up.
你可能是得流感了
You might have the flu.
我有几个同事得流感了
A bunch of guys at work had the flu,
我们共享一盒橙汁来着
and we all drink orange juice out of the same carton.
应该用杯子的
We should get cups.
卢克 听到了吗 是因为我得流感了
Luke, did you hear that?! I have the flu!
幸好我们没有共享那根腌黄瓜
Glad we didn't share that pickle.
大家好
Hey, everybody.
大家伙儿 伊森呢
Oh, hey, hey, guys. Where's Ethan?
他还在 去找他朋友去了
Oh, he's staying. He ran into some friends.
但迪兰被炒掉了 所以...
But Dylan got fired, so...
先别抓狂 不过我们得把迪兰捎回家
Don't freak out. We have to give him a ride home.
还有我们破镜重圆了
And we're back together.
没看林肯前 谁都别想走
Hey, no one goes home till we hit the Lincoln thing.
无聊
Yawn.
别做徒劳的反抗
Don't even try to fight it.
我们小时候 他就逼我们看
Yeah, he made us go when we were kids.
来吧各位 那可是机器人总统
Come on, people! It's a robotic president!
爱还来不及
What's not to love?
机器人总统
A robotic president?
我原计划是 带克莱尔和米奇尔回家
So my plan was, drive Claire and Mitchell home,
哄他们睡觉后
put them to bed,
给自己倒上一大杯威士忌
pour myself a big tumbler of scotch,
然后跟迪迪说离婚
and tell Dede it was over.
但在回家前 我们又去了一处地方
But on the way out, we made one last stop.
如果我们注定要灭亡
If destruction be our lot,
只有自己
we are ourselves
是自己的掘墓人
must be its author and finisher.
在自由人民组成的国家里
As a nation of free men,
我们必须经历过种种...
we must live through all times...
我不知道怎么回事
I don't know what happened.
可能是机器人林肯说到了男人的责任
Maybe it's what robot Lincoln said about a man's duty
或者要紧密"结合"在一起
or keeping the union together.
也可能就是我怂了
Maybe I just chickened out.
但我意识到和我的孩子们在一起
But I realized that staying with my kids
比离开妻子重要得多
was more important than leaving my wife.
这样的选择并非适合所有人
Now that's not the right decision for everyone,
但对我来说是绝对明智的
but it was the right decision for me.
凭着这信心
And in that faith,
让我们至终
let us, to the end,
能够恪尽职责
dare to do our duty
像我们心中理解的那样
as we understand it.
于是我坚持到了孩子们长大成人
So I stuck it out until they were grown...
杰 要不要一起洗个鸳鸯浴
Jay, you want to join me in the jacuzzi?
苍天有眼 苦尽甘来
And the universe rewarded me.
开始咯
Here we go!
爸 来个过山车拳拳碰
Hey, dad, roller coast fist bump.
什么情况
What was that?
肯定酷毙了
Is this gonna be so awesome!
闭上眼睛 感觉更爽
Close your eyes. It make it more fun.
是啊 的确更爽
Oh, yeah. That is more fun.